Lloyd: So now that you've completed
session three of unit one, it's
time to complete the relevant
section in the assessment booklet.
So if you open your assessment booklet and
scroll down to section three, and this is
about the software development life cycle.
As with the other two sections, the
learning objectives are at the top and
the relevant location in the course
materials if you need assistance
when formulating your answers.
So if you scroll down the question one,
it's asking you to identify and explain
in your own words, each of the key stages
of the software development life cycle.
So what you need to do in the left-hand
column, if you can just indicate the
exact stage in the cycle, so there's an
indication as to how many there are, but
obviously you need to give the name of the
stage and then explain what that stage is.
So what does that stage do?
What happens at that stage?
And that is an explanation, so try and
provide as much detail as you can in your
response for each of those explanations.
For question two, it's asking you: the
planning stage covers the requirements of
gathering analysis and design stages, do
a little research on this stage and in the
box below using your own words, describe
why the planning stage is important.
And it's asking you to make sure your
evidence websites and or books used.
This is about referencing any
information that you use from
the internet or external sources.
So the planning stage covers other
stages so sub-stages, shall we say?
So it covers the gathering,
analysis and design stages.
So what does it do?
Okay?
So what you need to do, why it is
important, what is the purpose of that?
What will it achieve?
What is the planning stage there to do?
What are the consequences if the
planning stage isn't done correctly?
Then for question three, it's
asking you in the box below,
list the actions that take place
during the implementation stage.
So if you, again, if you refer
back to the course materials,
what is the implementation stage
and what will happen during that?
So it's asking you to list, so you can
just bullet point or list the actions
that will take place during that stage.
For question four, it's asking
you to do some research on the
testing stage and in the box below
using your own words, explain why
the testing stage is important.
So why do we test?
What is the purpose of testing?
What would it achieve?
You could also give the consequences if
the testing stage isn't done correctly.
And then for question five, it's asking
you, again, to use your own words,
describe the actions that would take
place during the deployment stage.
So what happens during
the deployment stage?
What steps will be taken
during a deployment stage?
And for question six, again, it's
asked you to do a bit more research on
the maintenance stage and in the box
below using your own words, explain
why the maintenance stage is important.
So what is the purpose
of the maintenance stage?
What does it achieve?
What happens if it isn't done?
So again, this is an explain
question so try to provide
good detail in your response.
Once you're happy with your responses,
carry out a spelling and grammar check for
the whole document and proof read through
all three sections within your assessment.
Again, make sure that you're
happy with everything in there and
then you can save that and submit
it to your tutor for marking.
You can then move on to unit two.